[thuds]
[background chatter]
[click]
[Dalton on radio] America,
the land of the free,
home of the brave.
[Simon breathing heavily]
[Dalton on radio]
This is the greatest nation
in the history of mankind.
Good morning, Gulf Coast Six
listeners, and welcome
to The Nation, the only show
that tells the truth,
the only place asking
the big questions
and finding the big answers,
answers they don't want you to
hear, answers about what's
really happening in America
today.
I'm your host, Dalton Kirby, and
I'm here to give you the untold,
unbiased, and uncensored truth.
So if you don't like it,
change the [bleeped] station.
Today, I postulate who are we?
How do we define ourselves?
Who is America?
Well, I can tell you
what America is.
We're the largest oil exporter
in the world.
We produce and pioneer
revolutionary technology
in health and science.
We've created the most powerful
money market
the world has ever seen.
Real estate, manufacturing,
and agriculture are booming.
Industry, entertainment,
and gaming, all booming.
America is home to more
millionaires per capita
than anywhere on the planet.
[exhales]
[Dalton on radio]
And yet it's not enough.
We're beset with more division
than ever.
We are a nation divided, because
there is one untold truth
this world always needs:
a villain.
[shower running]
[Dalton on radio]
So who is that?
Once upon a time,
it was the Nazis,
then terrorists, and jihadists.
Now the left blames men
in suits.
The right blames
the West Coast elites.
But you know who's really
to blame, the cause of
all our problems?
[coffee pouring]
[Dalton on radio] Us.
We're to blame,
the middle class, working male.
You hearing me?
The cause of all our social
problems falls square
on our shoulders.
Listen, this is not advocation
of the marginalized working man.
We don't need sympathy,
and we don't need
preferential treatment.
We conquered empires, overthrew
tyrannical governments.
We created the radio, railroad,
television.
We discovered penicillin
and developed the atomic bomb.
Hell, we discovered flight,
and 66 years later,
we landed on the moon.
And do you know why we did it,
why we did all these things
that shaped the world
as we know it today?
We did it to better mankind.
We did it for our children's
children's children, and now
we're the villain of
all the world's problems.
We've let them do it to us,
to our country.
Hell, they've destroyed
our freedom of speech.
We can't even practice
civil discourse.
Even now, there are people out
there whose flesh is literally
burning because of what I just
said, but it's the truth.
So don't quit.
Don't stop fighting for what
you know to be true and right.
The real price of everything,
what everything really costs
to the man who wants
to acquire it, is the toil
and trouble of acquiring it.
I'm Dalton Kirby,
and this is The Nation.
We'll be right back after a
word from our spon--
-[radio clicks off]
-[seatbelt clicks]
[sighs]
[mechanical whirring]
[panting]
-There he is.
-[thudding]
[thunder rumbles]
What's going on?
You know Tony's out, right?
How's the new boss?
[Will] Good morning, guys.
My name's Will Jeffries.
I'ma be taking over the
daily operations here at MTI.
I'd love to meet with each one
of you individually to discuss
the new direction of
the company, but meanwhile,
we got three trucks going out.
I've spoken with Gary Parker,
who's elected Dave's team
to run prep.
The rest of you guys
are dismissed.
Thank you.
All right.
Hey, buddy,
you're with us today, okay?
-[rain pattering]
-[sighs]
So what do you think, man?
Think about what?
Fucking Tony, Will,
all the bullshit, new guy.
All right with me.
The fuck do you do, man?
The battery.
[Gary]
Hey, you wanna grab a beer, man?
One beer.
I'll treat. You're good.
-You said, yes. I heard yes.
-[Simon] Let's go.
[Gary] Oh bro, look at this one,
this one, this one, this one.
Literally all of these you can
make at home, dude.
What exactly are you showing me
here?
Bro, this is like insanity,
dude.
You can literally make this
from your fucking house.
Like a printer, man.
And it's completely
environmental friendly, right?
It's made from like corn starch
and uh, fucking sugar cane.
Look, see?
Solid PLA thermoplastic polymer.
It's 100% legit,
completely legal.
[laughs]
You say that until the feds
come kicking in your front door
thinking you're a goddamn
terrorist.
Oh, come on, man.
Look, you can
make your own guns,
you just can't sell that shit.
Believe me,
I've done my research.
Oh yeah? [laughs] Where
have you done your research?
On the internet?
The World Wide Web? [laughs]
Jackass.
And everything on there is true.
[pats] All right, come on.
-What are you doing?
-I gotta get out of here.
-No, no. No.
-No, no, no, bro.
Come on, let me get this please.
-You sure?
-Yeah, man.
Thanks for putting me
on the crew today.
I didn't know what was going on.
It's what we do, man.
Can I stop by your house real
quick and pick up your edger?
Becca wants me to finish
the yard this week.
Yeah, man.
-Angie would love to see ya.
-Yeah.
And I won't take a year to get
it back.
All right, bud.
We rolling?
-Let's go.
-All right.
[clears throat]
-[TV playing]
-[door opens]
[Simon] Like Metal Man.
That oughta be his handle.
[Gary speaking indistinctly]
[laughs]
Hey, baby.
-Hey.
-How are you?
Good.
How's she doing?
Good. We had a good day.
Of course, you did.
She's a fighter,
just like her old man.
[laughs]
Hey Simon, how's Rebecca?
Great.
Working, you know, keeping busy.
Tony's replacement started
today.
We'll see how long that lasts.
-[Angela sighs]
-He already replaced two crews.
[Angela] Oof.
I bet that went over well.
Real crowd pleaser.
[laughs]
All right.
Edger's in the shed.
Glad she's feeling okay.
[background TV chatter]
[car approaching]
[car door opens]
[car door closes]
[door creaks open]
[tense music playing]
[door closes]
[♪♪♪]
Becca?
[pants]
[car approaches]
[takes deep breaths]
[Rebecca] Simon?
[footsteps approaching]
[Rebecca] Simon.
Jesus, what happened?
[sighs]
[Officer Wilcox]
And that was it?
You checked the garage
after and noticed the door?
[Simon] Yeah, right after.
I made a list of all
the jewelry they took,
some things of my mom's.
I wrote out a description.
Okay. So how long does it
usually take to find these guys?
Like, what's the deal
with this kind of thing?
[Officer Wilcox]
Well, that depends.
You know, usually we pick guys
like this up after they try
to pawn something,
catch 'em with the merchandise,
or we'll get 'em on
a traffic stop,
catch 'em on parole violation,
and suddenly they
start talking, you know?
[scoffs] So we're just supposed
to let them get away with this?
No.
No one's getting away with this.
We're gonna catch 'em.
It's just gonna-- it's just
gonna take some time
What if they come back?
I don't know if this helps,
but it's probably the same guys
that have hit four other homes
around here recently.
They drive around
with a programmed remote
and they just see
which garage opens.
It's random.
You weren't targeted.
[sighs]
And what about homeowners?
Does it cover property?
[clicks tongue] We rent.
Here's the address
to the station.
Come by, fill out a property
report.
That's it?
[Officer Wilcox] I'm sorry.
Try to have a good night.
[card tapping]
Well, great.
Babe.
[footsteps receding]
[clinking]
[sighs] I can look at some
of the pawn shops,
try to find the jewelry.
Don't even bother.
It's fucking gone.
-Hey.
-[Rebecca sighs]
Hey.
-We'll get through this.
-Yeah.
Just fuck them.
-Fuck these entitled assh--
-[plate shatters]
-Fuck!
-Are you okay?
[Rebecca sighs]
It's just-- it's such
an invasion, you know?
Just what gives them the right
to break in
and steal our stuff, huh?
Who the fuck do they think
they are?
Oh, I just--
[sighs] You're-- you're right.
It's-- it's fine.
You know what? You're right.
It's fine.
We'll-- we'll get through this.
I-- I need a Band-Aid.
[footsteps receding]
[takes deep breath]
[dramatic music playing]
[♪♪♪]
[TV playing]
[Dalton on radio] I have
a stark warning for you today.
They will use anything and
everything they can to defraud
and tarnish your name.
Anything.
BBC News reports in a recent
lawsuit against Bob Dylan
that he's being accused of
sexual misconduct
and grooming of a minor in 1965.
Did you hear me?
1965.
That was over 60 years ago.
Now hear me out.
[breathes heavily]
[Dalton on radio] I'm not saying
the allegations aren't true,
but I wanna ask, why now?
Let me be clear.
I don't know Bob Dylan,
I don't like Bob Dylan's music.
I don't care about Bob Dylan.
But what burns me up is the
fact that we aren't judged
in the courts anymore.
We are judged in the court of
public opinion.
The truth doesn't
matter to these people.
All that matters is clicks,
and ad revenues,
and opportunity.
Am I saying Bob Dylan
is innocent?
No.
Am I saying the incident
in question shouldn't
be investigated?
No.
But when Time Magazine says,
and I quote, "A legend has died.
The untold truth of Bob Dylan's
dark past", that's a load of BS.
We don't know anything
about what happened,
who was involved,
what choices or decisions
were made, and yet we as
a collective body
have already decided
what the truth is.
Stay with us, people.
We'll be right back with a
whole lot more to talk about.
[car door closes]
[door opens and closes]
[locker opens]
[scoffs]
So we're just back to coming in
whenever we want, huh?
[fridge door opens]
[sighs] Come on.
Jesus Christ, Ward,
this ain't a fucking day camp.
[door opens and closes]
[locker closes]
[knocking, door opens]
You said you wanted to see me?
Yeah.
Hey Simon, come on in.
-Have a seat.
-[door closes]
You know, I was looking at
this, Simon, and it looks like
you've been uh, at MTI what?
Going on eight years now.
[Simon] Mm.
How do you like it?
Yeah, I like it.
It's a job.
Well, it says you filed for
a foreman's position this year.
Is that right?
Mm.
[Will] But you didn't get it.
No.
They tell you why?
[Simon]
It was about six months ago.
Um, Gary, his daughter got um,
really sick.
Really sick,
and wasn't doing well.
And um, he missed a few days
and then uh,
I guess he didn't call in
or something.
And-- so Dave got up in my
face, because I defended him.
I guess that's why it says
there's an altercation, huh?
I backed off and then he swung
on me.
I swung back.
I got two weeks'
suspension um, without pay.
You know what he got? [laughs]
Nothing, 'cause he got hit.
[Will] Mm-hmm.
So everything fell on me.
Listen, man, Simon,
I like to do
things a little different.
I like for the past
to be the past.
Give people a fresh start just
to see what happens, you know?
Your work record's really good,
Simon.
Turnaround's solid.
You're always meeting
your quota.
What do you say we uh, just
keep doing what you're doing
and let's revisit that foreman
position.
Yeah?
Uh, that sounds--
that sounds terrific.
[Will] Good.
Thank you.
It's my pleasure, son.
You let me know
if I can help you, all right?
Any way. [patting]
-I will.
-[Will] You got it.
Thanks.
[door opens and closes]
[thudding]
-[spraying]
-[footsteps descending]
[laughs]
What'd he say?
Huh?
The new guy.
Good.
I may be up for foreman again.
Fuck off.
Bro, that's fucking great, dude.
He said he's starting fresh
with everyone.
That's good, I suppose.
Well, shit.
Hey man,
I got a question for you.
Yeah.
Can you take me shooting?
I mean-- [sighs]
I've only waited four years
for you to ask me.
Yes, dude, 100%.
I think it's a must.
Fuck, let's go tomorrow.
Um, all right, yeah.
Yeah, tomorrow.
Um, can we go in the morning?
Because Rebecca's hosting
this company barbecue
in the afternoon,
and I have to be there already.
Of course, man.
She invited me and Angie, too.
Her mom's gonna come watch
Stephanie for a few hours just
to give us some time.
That'll be good for you.
Yeah, it'll be a nice break,
right?
[inhales]
Uh, Bullseye opens at 9:00
a.m., so like I can just
text you the address
and we can meet there.
-There it is.
-So we're locked in?
-Locked in.
-All right, bye.
-Going shooting.
-I'll catch you.
[door opens and closes]
[whirring & spraying
in background]
[man 2 on TV]
Lost three of my teeth, too.
[man 3 on TV] All right, so
you lost. Next time you'll win.
I'll show you how.
Take a look at Joe McCloy here.
[chuckles]
[man 3 on TV]
He used to be my boss.
Now I'm his.
What's the difference between
me and him?
We breathe the same air,
sleep in the same hotel.
He used to own it.
-Now it belongs to me.
-You okay?
Yeah. [clears throat]
[man 3 on TV]
Drink the same bourbon.
Look, same manicure,
same cufflinks,
but there's only one difference.
What?
[man 3 on TV]
We don't get the same girls.
Why?
[man 3 on TV] Because
women know the difference.
[sighs]
[man 3 on TV]
They got instinct.
I'm uh, I've just been thinking
about things.
You know, wondering if maybe
we should buy a house.
You know?
Something a little more secure.
Something that we could maybe,
I don't know, build a family in.
We haven't really talked
about the future,
you know, marriage, kids.
I mean, yeah.
Do you want those things?
Yeah. I just, you know.
Yeah, I just?
-Simon.
-Yes.
I mean, I just uh, I hadn't
given it much thought, 'cause
I-- I was just watching TV.
Well, that's what
people our age do
after being
together for half a decade.
-Mm.
-Right?
They get married
and they start a family.
Mm-hmm. No, I know.
I-- I know.
I just-- I wasn't, uh--
What?
What, Simon?
Becca, there's a-- there's a
lot of shit happening out there.
-[scoffs]
-And-- and-- and
I'm just saying right now--
Mm-hmm.
Doesn't seem like the
best time to bring a child
into this fucked-up world
we live in.
[clicks tongue] Wow.
Well, do you see how--
-[scoffs]
-I--
Okay.
-[glass clunks]
-Sure.
I'm just say-- I think you're
misunderstanding what I'm--
Yep. Got it.
[Rebecca sighs]
[door slams shut]
[takes deep breath]
[gun clicks]
[gunshots]
[Gary laughing]
[Gary] There it is.
You see that?
Here, come over here.
You're good. You're good.
-Okay.
All right, I'm gonna tell you
some things, okay?
Some you'll retain,
some you won't, okay?
This is a Glock 17.
Holds 9mm rounds, okay?
Doesn't really have a big kick,
but you still want
to have a firm grip on it,
right?
Always keep that finger
straight, right?
-You see that?
-Mm-hmm.
Always keep the finger
straight, right?
So you got the slide, got the
chamber, got the magazine.
You rack it, it's ready to go,
okay?
But be careful.
On Glocks, there's no manual
safety, so as soon as
you chamber a round, it's hot,
okay?
So I'm giving you
a loaded weapon,
but I'm gonna let you rack it
to make it hot,
-okay?
-Okay.
-Yeah.
-Got it?
-All right.
-Okay.
Here you go. It's good.
-Oh, easy.
-Yeah.
Hold on.
All right.
Yeah. Square up, bud.
Square up with your legs.
Yeah. Okay.
-A little bend.
-Like that?
-Yeah.
Yeah. Let's see how you grab it
just on your own instincts.
-Okay. And just rack it.
-Rack it. Yeah.
Rack it hard, forceful.
[gun clicks]
Okay.
More on that later.
Yeah fire it up, man.
Give it a shot.
Okay.
Finger.
This.
[gunshots]
[Gary] Right on, man.
All right, put it down.
All right.
All right, let me get that.
Let me look, let me look,
let me look. See what we got.
[target carrier whirring]
Well, shit, it's not bad.
-Gave him a gimpy arm, right?
-Yeah.
Look, all it takes is one,
right?
Yeah.
It's a lot harder than it looks.
It kind of is.
-[laughs]
-See that right there?
That's called, "jerking".
It means you're moving
the muzzle away from the target
at the last second, right?
It's a physical and mental
issue, but primarily
it's a mental issue.
Explain.
All right. Well--
[clears throat]
As a shooter, you wanna learn
to put your mental focus
on the trigger press
and try to train
your jerking movement away
from your mechanics, right?
Which is caused by the uh,
compression of the grip of
the gun, which causes the hand
to move the muzzle away
from the target just as
the bullet exits.
Does that make sense?
-Got it.
-Okay.
So let's do this back out.
[target carrier whirring]
Boom. Okay.
Pick this up, right?
Watch those hands.
-Okay. You seeing?
-Uh-huh.
You landed here,
which is pretty good.
Kind of natural instinct,
sort of.
-Yeah.
-Not really, but-- right?
-Mm-hmm.
-Okay.
All right.
A firm grip, light squeeze.
Just like that.
Got it?
Oh, got it.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
-I got it.
-All right.
I'm gonna hand it to you again,
okay?
Okay. [laughs]
-You're doing great, man.
-Yeah.
Just remember, don't anticipate
the squeeze, okay?
And just breathe, man.
Breathe.
Yeah. Breathe.
[takes deep breath]
Breathe.
[gunshot]
It's okay, man.
Look, steady up and try again.
Okay? It's mechanics, right?
Mechanics, repetition.
-Yeah.
-Doing great, dude.
[gunshots]
[Gary] What?
Did fucking Yosemite Sam
just walk into this bitch?
[laughs]
That was really good, dude.
-[laughs]
-[phone vibrating]
I'm a good fucking teacher.
One second.
Baby, what's up?
Um, okay.
Uh, call Doctor Hoffman.
Tell her to come right over.
I'll be home in 10 minutes.
Yeah. Okay.
I love you.
Oh, fuck.
You okay?
Uh, yeah. Stephanie's
having another one of her--
[sighs]
Goddammit. Where the fuck?
Yeah. Uh, yeah, I'm fine, man.
Uh, you got this place
for 45 minutes, okay?
I'll get that from you later,
okay?
I just-- I just gotta roll, man.
-I gotta roll.
-Yeah.
-You sure you're all right?
-Yeah, man.
I'm, uh-- yeah, I'm good.
[door opens and closes]
-[gunshot]
-[sizzling]
[Cory] I just think the
law has done this the right way.
You guys ready for round two?
-Yeah.
-Yeah?
-You ready for another one?
-[Cory] Yes, of course.
[Rebecca] You as well? Yeah.
No problem. I'm used to it.
-[Sharon] Yeah. How you doing?
-[Rebecca] Good. Yeah, not bad.
-[Harris] Thank you.
-You want a burger?
-I'd love one.
-Yeah, you do cheese?
-Yeah, cheese. Cheese please.
-Cheese?
Okay. Yeah, I know
you're [indistinct speech]
-Yeah. Right.
-Yes, of course.
-Thank you.
-[both laugh]
Uh, Sharon wants
a veggie burger.
Can you throw an extra patty
on for Cory?
[background chatter]
[soft music playing]
[Harris] You can tell
what he's trying to do.
[Cory] Yeah, for sure.
[Harris] [laughs] Like, he
tries to play it off, right?
Yeah, he totally does.
He tries to sound like
this level-headed authority,
you know, with all this
compassion and wisdom.
[laughs] Yeah.
But then you can smell it.
[sniffs, laughs]
The insanity just
beneath the surface?
Basically.
Look, in reality, he's fucking
delusional and dangerous.
I mean, the rhetoric
that he spews is harmful
and destructive at best.
It's vile.
[Simon] Who's that?
[Cory] Dalton Kirby.
-Hm.
-He's a crazy radio host.
No, yeah, I know who he is.
And who are you?
Uh, Cor-- sorry,
I'm uh, Cory Harris.
Um, Rebecca and I work together.
Simon.
Rebecca's boyfriend.
Uh, pleasure to meet you, Simon.
Um-- [laughs]
So what, you're like a--
you're a fan of Dalton Kirby?
I didn't say that, no.
I just said I know who he is.
What are your thoughts on him?
[sighs]
I think it's getting crazy
out there.
Crazy how?
Nobody cares about the truth
anymore.
We're constantly being fed lies
by a broken system.
Right, and you think a man
who profits off of selling lies
for a living is
the voice of reason?
[laughs] Not at all.
No, no, no, no, no.
I think he's a complete
and total whack job.
-[Cory and Harris laughing]
-Okay.
Okay. Agreed.
But you and I both know
who the real problem is, right?
Who's the real problem?
Problem causing all the shit,
the economic turmoil,
social injustices.
You know who's doing all that,
right?
Us, the working man.
Mm.
We've had it too good
for too long.
It's an unfair system, right?
Right. Yes, yes, that's why
I'm such a big proponent
of social equity.
[Simon] Absolutely.
Topple the system.
Can I get you another?
Uh, yeah. Thank you.
[Simon] You got it.
Wow. [laughs]
He knows his stuff.
[Harris] Sure does, man.
[laughs]
-[Cory] Yes, yeah.
-[Rebecca] Yeah.
[Cory] Oh, man.
[grunts, sniffles]
[indistinct chatter]
[Cory] I had a dream
about peanut, airline.
[indistinct chatter]
-[Rebecca laughs]
-[Cory] Yeah.
[Rebecca] [indistinct speech]
We were, um--
[indistinct speech]
-[laughs]
-Oh my God.
You walked into the door with--
[Cory] I-- I don't wear heels.
I haven't figured them out yet.
[Harris] Watch out.
[Rebecca] Did you wear heels
that are like--
[Cory] Yeah.
[crickets chirping]
[Rebecca] Hm.
[instrumental music playing]
[Rebecca sighs]
[dishes clank]
[tap running]
Hey.
Are you okay?
I'm sorry.
Hey.
[kisses]
[moaning]
[Dalton on radio]
Do white men have problems?
[dramatic music playing]
[Dalton on radio]
Yes, absolutely.
So do Black men, brown men,
and yellow men.
Oh, no, I said yellow.
I don't care.
Green men, purple men,
orange men,
it doesn't matter the color
of your skin,
we all have problems, people.
Now, this is not an abdication
of responsibility,
but an articulation that
no one group is responsible
for all our societal problems.
We must, all of us, bear the
weight of that responsibility
equally and unbiasedly.
We've allowed this to happen.
If we are going to have
a functioning
and healthy democracy,
we need to be open
to civil discourse, people.
We need to pull back the cloth
and look at the festering wounds
and sores under the surface
and openly discuss them.
Words, not violence,
change men's heart.
But sometimes when words don't
work, all that's left
is the constitution of one
man's soul, his conviction.
[pen scribbling]
[keys clacking]
[background chatter]
[officer 1]
All right. Anything else?
Sir, anything else?
No, I'm good.
-All right.
-[paper rustling]
Here you go, boss.
You're all set.
-Thanks.
-[phone ringing]
Mm-hmm.
Hey, what's up?
[Gary on phone] Hey, man.
You around?
♪ There's something
about the way that woman walks ♪
♪ She can heat it up hot,
bring it down real cold ♪
♪ She's got that
sad little look women want ♪
♪ She's got that class, baby ♪
Hey, what's going on?
[clicks tongue]
It's not good, man.
What's wrong?
Huh?
[Gary clicks tongue] It spread.
So,
uh,
I'm-- I'm not ready.
Can't--
I can't lose my baby girl.
[Simon] Hey, listen.
We don't know--
[Gary sobs]
She's gonna-- she's gonna die.
Oh, fuck.
Fuck.
I'm not fucking ready, man.
Ah.
Fucking hate him.
If there's a God,
he doesn't give a shit about us
and he never did.
[sniffles]
Fuck him, you know?
[sighs]
[objects clattering]
Hey.
It's okay.
I got this.
[objects clattering]
Mm-hmm.
[birds chirping]
[sighs]
[door opens]
[birds chirping]
[somber music playing]
[tinkling]
[sighs]
-[toilet lid thuds]
-[flushes]
[water running]
[footsteps]
[Gary] It's broken, isn't it?
This whole thing, this system.
How is it fair that they limit
care to a little girl,
because her insurance doesn't
cover it?
How is that a thing?
I did all I could for her.
She's gone.
And all we have is an empty
room and a fuck ton of debt.
She was so beautiful.
She was the most beautiful
thing in the world.
Now she's gone, and I hate it,
because it's unfair.
It is un--
[groans]
[Gary inhales shakily]
[Gary clicks tongue, sighs]
Ugh.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, man.
Thank y'all for being here.
[sniffles]
Oh, God almighty.
[grunts]
[emotional music playing]
[sighs]
[Dalton on radio]
"It was then he knew
the reckoning would come.
If not today, nor tomorrow,
it existed all the same.
And it was alive on some distant
horizon, awaiting our arrival.
And like a great storm
of unyielding power
unraveled so violently
upon the Earth,
so too would our nascent gods
awaken and usher the old way
into the hands of death.
And the slaves rose
up against their masters
and brought them
to their knees."
Wow.
-That's powerful.
-[beeps]
That's Nik Perleros,
and this was a short excerpt
from his new book, Nascent Gods,
Apocalypse, and Paradise.
Nik, thanks for coming
on the show.
[Nik on radio]
Thanks for having me.
[Dalton on radio] So tell us
a little bit about the title,
Nascent Gods, Apocalypse,
and Paradise.
What's that mean?
[Nik on radio]
Nascent God is something
that I refer to
quite often in the book.
The word itself means something
coming or having recently come
into existence.
So Nascent Gods is inferring
that gods, air quotes,
since you listeners
can't see me, have come
or are coming into existence.
So the question is,
who are they?
Who are these gods
and what do they want?
[Dalton on radio] Do we
encounter them in the story?
Do we get to see them?
[Nik on radio]
The new gods?
Yes, and no.
Not to go too deep
into the story, but it's really
an allegory about the god inside
each of us and how society's
reaching a great awakening.
And when the common man realizes
he has the power of God
inside him, he can control and
shape the universe around him.
[Dalton on radio]
Wow. That's powerful.
It's a great story as well.
It's on the New York Times
bestseller list right now.
You can get a copy on Kindle,
iBook, hardcover, et cetera.
-[Dave] Just y--
-[air hissing]
[Dave] You have to
all be on the same page.
That's why the measurements
are wrong.
See, l-- look here.
See, 34 11/16 of an inch.
Now this is-- this is the--
the-- the--
the tricky part here.
-So you have the ramp here--
-Hey, Dave.
[Dave] Up here, and so
what I'm trying to understand
is this whole thing--
-Dave!
-Is kind of-- What?
Listen, is it all right if I uh,
cut out a little early today?
I got some stuff I need to do.
[scoffs] No.
We're short three guys and we're
already behind on the JPL case
that's going out,
so I need you here.
L-- look at all this to do, and
they still-- they still haven't
gotten to the ramp yet.
Okay? So get to work.
So, um, ins-- the installation,
right?
[hammering, spraying
in background]
[knocks]
Oh, hey Simon.
What can I do for you?
Gary call in?
Gary?
No.
No, he didn't.
Listen--
[exhales] I'm sorry to hear
about his daughter, man.
That's terrible.
Yeah.
Hey, listen, you mind if I uh,
leave a little early?
We're almost done here.
Did you talk to Dave?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
He said, you know, uh, it's all
good if I just come up here
and clear it with you.
If we ain't behind,
I don't got a problem with it.
[phone ringing]
Yeah.
It's Will.
Yeah. No, we're good.
Yeah.
Yep, we're in.
[birds chirping]
[kids shouting]
[car door opens and closes]
[door opens]
Hey, man.
-Bud.
-What are you doing here?
Just coming to see you.
You want a beer?
Sure.
[grunts]
There you go, man.
Thanks, pal.
[sighs]
I was telling Angie,
we gotta get a sprinkler
and hose for this lawn, man.
[laughs]
Everything is dead.
They got a 50-footer on sale
at Depot right now.
I think it's like 40 bucks.
Pretty good deal.
40 bucks?
Goddamn.
That is pretty good.
Yeah, we're talking about
redoing the kitchen,
maybe the bathroom, although
I'm starting to think that maybe
the kitchen is a better idea,
right?
Like equity-wise.
You know,
people love their solid surfaces
and stainless steel,
all that bullshit.
Y'all still thinking of moving?
Thinking about it.
Her mom's got a place
up in Taos, incredible
for big game hunting, right?
We should go sometime.
Yeah.
In fact, I think New Mexico
draws tags pretty early,
like July.
Maybe we go in the fall?
Let's do it.
Yeah, I think so.
Yeah, something has gotta
be done about this lawn.
[laughs]
It's just out of control.
Dead. [laughs]
Hey, man.
You all good?
[clicks tongue] I'm good, man.
Little hungover this morning.
Hair of the dog.
[laughs]
[birds chirping]
Hear those birds?
Yeah.
It's nice.
[inhales]
All right.
All right. [grunts]
I gotta get back.
I just wanted to check on you.
Thanks, man.
All right.
Tell Angie I said uh, goodbye.
I sure will, bud.
See you tomorrow.
[footsteps receding]
[gunshots]
[gun clicks]
[somber music playing]
[gunshot]
[sniffles]
[sighs]
[footsteps receding]
[gunshot]
[thuds]
[birds chirping]
[door opens and closes]
What?
Hey.
What? What's wrong?
-What's going on?
-[Rebecca cries]
-[Rebecca] I'm sorry.
-What happened?
[Rebecca sniffles]
[Rebecca] I'm so sorry.
Rebecca, what happened?
[car approaching]
[♪♪♪]
[door opens and closes]
[Dalton on radio]
If you missed us this morning,
we're talking about home defense
and general firearm safety
practices,
but I wanna pivot here.
I think there is something more
important, an undercurrent
under the surface of all this.
How do we protect our country,
our communities, ourselves?
I think we make social
concessions that cause more
damage than good.
It's like we're afraid to stand
up against the system.
We're a-- afraid to fight back.
Sometimes I think this whole
thing needs to come down.
There comes a time when the
operation of the machine becomes
so odious, it makes you so sick
that you can't even participate.
You can't even be passive
about it.
That's when someone will rise up
and throw their body
upon the gears and wheels,
upon the levers and the gross
apparatuses, and make it stop.
[machine whirring]
[Dalton on radio]
We've got to make it stop.
[Will] Yo, Ward!
[knocking on door]
[door opens]
Come on in, Simon.
Shut the door, please.
[door closes]
You wanna tell me what happened
the other day
when you was in here?
Had an emergency.
[scoffs]
Yeah, right, an emergency.
Look, guys, I'm in a really
tough spot here.
[Dave] No, Will,
I'm in a tough spot here.
Now, come on, how many more
times are you gonna keep giving
this guy a free pass, huh?
Trucks weren't prepped properly.
They had missing gear,
incorrect equipment.
Now, he left Tom and Victor
completely holding the bag,
and the other thing was,
-was that--
-Dave, Dave, that's enough.
He's a selfish prick, Will.
Do you not understand?
Look, I don't have a problem
with him personally,
but I do have a very serious
problem with his fucking garbage
work ethic and him not liking me
calling him out on his shit,
which seems to be the constant--
[Will] Dave, Dave.
Buddy, give us a moment.
Look, something's gotta change
and it's gotta happen now.
[door shuts]
Simon, I'm really trying to
work with you, son.
You need to help me.
You don't care about the truth.
I'm being judged in the court
of public opinion here.
The truth doesn't matter to you.
The truth?
You wanna tell me what the
truth is, Simon?
Look, buddy, I'm feel bad
as anybody about Gary.
Gary was a solid guy.
But you, my friend, you need to
take some time to get
your head on right.
Look, I tell you what.
I'm gonna give you my number.
All right?
This is my cell.
[pen scribbling]
Here.
You call me if you wanna talk.
Meantime, just take the rest
of the week off.
Come back when you got things
sorted out.
It's no big deal.
I'll talk to Dave.
I'm sorry.
[door opens and closes]
[Dalton on radio] I've been
talking with our producers
and um, I think
we've come up with something
you're gonna like.
On September 24th, we are going
to host a live show
at White Hall Convention Center.
I want you to come out,
show your support.
We're gonna peacefully assemble
together
and show this corrupt system
what being a real patriot means.
[phone ringing]
[Dalton on radio]
Are you a patriot?
[phone ringing]
Hello?
[Angela on phone] Simon?
Yeah.
[Angela on phone]
Can you come over?
I need your help with something.
Yeah. Yeah, I'll be right over.
[sighs]
It's over there.
All of it?
All of it.
[dramatic music playing]
[footsteps receding]
[♪♪♪]
[Dalton on radio]
This is not financial advice.
I have to say that,
so you don't sue my ass,
but here it is, the untold,
unbiased truth.
Stay away from crypto.
It's a racket.
Plus, it ain't backed
by nothing.
It isn't FDIC insured.
It's not based on anything.
Now, I know some of
you are saying,
"Well, what about the dollar?
It's not backed by anything
either."
Well, on the contrary, people.
Remember that little war
we've been fighting
for, what, 20 years?
Well, do you know what happened
after that war?
The good old US of A became
the largest oil exporter
in the world.
That means if you wanna buy
petrol, you gotta buy it in USD.
So as long as the world keeps
using oil,
and I'll give you a hint,
they are, the old greenback
ain't going anywhere.
Don't worry about it.
Keep cash on hand
for when this correction hits,
'cause, friends,
it's gonna be a doozy.
[door opens and closes]
Good morning.
How can I help you?
Oh, I was just passing by
and I uh, I saw the station.
Oh, great.
Yeah.
I was wondering if, uh,
Mr. Kirby was in. Dalton?
He is, but he's live right now,
so--
Oh, no, I know.
I was just listening to him.
Um, I was wondering if I could
talk with him for a minute.
Um, well--
[Simon] No, no,
no, not right now.
No, I-- I'll wait.
I can wait.
I know he's on the air, so.
How about this?
What's your name?
I'll leave a message.
[Simon]
No, you don't need to do that.
I just wanna talk with him
for a minute, that's all.
Mm.
Just give me one moment.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Stay right there.
Go ahead.
[heels clacking]
[chuckles]
Hello. I'm Peter Ellis.
I'm the station producer
for WFBX.
Oh, hey.
It's nice to meet you.
I'm uh, Simon. Simon Ward.
Nice to meet you, Simon.
W-- uh, what can I do for you?
Well, like I was just telling
the nice lady there,
um, I was driving by and I saw
the station,
and I just wanted to, you know,
pop in and say a few kind words
to Mr. Kirby.
Well, we love our supporters.
So you wanna give him a message?
We'll be sure to get it to him.
Well, I was hoping
that I could tell him myself.
Oh. Well,
we don't really do that, Simon.
Uh, security reasons.
I'm sure you understand.
Yeah. Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I get it.
But uh, you give us
that message and uh,
w-- we'll make sure he gets it.
Yeah, yeah.
Yes, sir. Um.
[takes deep breath]
Um.
I'm-- I'm an avid listener.
My name is uh, Simon Ward.
I just told you that.
And-- and I wanted to say how
much I appreciate everything
you do for--
Well, thank you.
Uh, say, are you a donor?
Actually, no.
Oh, well,
a bit of advice, Simon.
Uh, Dalton really appreciates
donors,
and he especially
appreciates messages
from donors, so FYI.
I can do that.
Uh, everything is available
to our members,
uh, including some um,
s-- special content
and behind the scenes--
-Mm-hmm.
-Uh, blogs, interviews,
seminars, book recommendations,
there's a lot more.
Yeah.
So if you just go
to WFBXTheNation.com.
[Simon] Mm-hmm.
It's all right there.
Hm. Thanks.
[Peter] Well, great.
It was really nice to meet you,
Simon.
[Simon]
Thanks for being a voice.
Thanks for being an unafraid
voice that speaks the truth,
especially in times like these.
Everything is.
-.everything is so broken.
-Yes. Yes, it is.
The system is broken,
and it's designed to trap men
in it, to beat them down
and to trap them, and wants you
to do the 9:00 to 5:00 thing
to get the house, the family,
the dog, while piling up
mounds of debt so high
that you're forced
to continually be a slave
to-- to their game, their way.
Wow.
That is really powerful, Simon.
Thank you.
Someone needs to break
the system.
Like Dalton says, someone needs
to stand up to the ruling class
and show them that we're the
ones that have the power,
that we make the world go round.
'Cause look what they did.
Look what they did.
They turned the American dream
into a trap.
It's like this-- it's a
never-ending maze that, no end.
There's no end.
You can't win, but they make
you believe that you can win.
And they make you believe
you can win by making
all these false promises to
you, promises of promotions,
like you're moving up, promises
of more money, more success.
And the whole time
you're living this life,
this-- this programmed life,
you're never building
your own wealth.
You're just building theirs.
It's like a.
You didn't write
any of that down?
[Peter laughs]
I got it right here, I promise.
I'm gonna need you to leave.
[Simon] Write it down.
I need you to leave.
Call security.
No, don't call security.
I didn't do anything wrong.
-[Peter] Simon.
-Just write down what I said.
I need you to leave right now!
And I need you to listen to me!
Listen to me talk!
[tense music playing]
-Call the police.
-No.
Don't call the po--
I didn't do any--
[Carl] Sir.
[Simon] You didn't even see
what happened. I didn't--
Sir, you need to leave
right now.
-You weren't even here.
-Sir.
[door opens and closes]
[panting]
What the fuck was that?
You okay?
[Lilly] Yeah.
[upbeat music playing]
♪ I feel it ♪
♪ Watch me bleed ♪
♪ Stalk the sky ♪
♪ Fuck your dreams ♪
♪ I feel it ♪
♪ Watch me bleed ♪
[door opens, closes]
Simon?
Simon.
[panting]
What is this?
Where-- where did you get these?
They're Gary's.
Why are they here?
Angela asked me to get
rid of 'em.
So get rid of them.
Can we talk about this?
There's nothing to say.
I don't want these in our home.
[Simon]
I'd like to talk about it.
I feel compelled to protect us.
Protect us?
From what?
[scoffs]
Them.
Them?
There are people out there
that want to hurt us.
Those assholes that broke
into our home.
[sighs]
[Simon] There are a ton of
other people that are doing--
Simon, nobody is after us.
That was a random break-in.
-You don't understand.
-Understand what?
That our g-- garage looks like
a goddamn armory?
You don't understand what's
happening in the world.
[sighs] Oh, well please,
why don't you enlighten me then?
No one's looking out for us.
No one cares about us.
The cops aren't doing anything.
They didn't arrest anyone.
No one was held accountable.
It's fucking chaos out there,
and no one is
doing anything about it.
[Rebecca] What?
What the fuck are you
talking about, Simon?
We just have to be prepared,
that's all.
Okay, this conversation is
starting to scare me.
Good. You should be scared.
Everyone should be scared.
Everyone should be
fucking terrified.
-No.
-That's the truth.
Simon, no.
I'm not going to live in fear.
All right?
Fear is not good.
Get rid of them.
I'm not gonna do that.
They're Gary's.
[Rebecca sighs]
I'm pregnant, Simon.
You have a child coming,
and I am not raising them
around this.
What?
[Rebecca]
I'm about six weeks along.
I-- [sighs]
I was gonna tell you
when I found out,
but then Gary.
No, it's okay.
I'll get rid of them.
-I'll get rid of them.
-[Rebecca sighs] Thank you.
[Rebecca sighs]
[Dalton on radio]
I've talked about this before,
and I'll say it again.
The 308 is the best all-around
cartridge
for most shooters'
and hunters' needs.
[Pete on radio]
Yeah, it's good.
I like it.
[Dalton on radio]
It's reliable out to 800 yards.
It can be kind of expensive,
but--
[Pete on radio]
It's not that expensive anymore.
[Dalton on radio] Well, the
rounds I buy can be expensive,
but what you're buying shows up
on target, 'cause it's accurate.
[Pete on radio] Yeah, it is.
It is very accurate.
I got my first elk with a 308.
I was up in uh, where was I?
Colville National Forest,
Washington.
Really pretty country up there.
[Dalton on radio]
If you're just tuning in,
we're with Pete Richardson,
world-renowned sportsman,
hunter guide, novelist,
and all-around badass.
[Pete laughs]
Well, thanks for having me.
[Dalton on radio]
Thanks for being here.
So tell us, what goes through
the mind of a big game hunter?
What are you thinking about
out there?
[Pete on radio] There's
a lot to being a successful
big game hunter,
but I think at its core
it's the understanding
and recognition of patience.
You have to have patience.
You can't rush anything.
Tracking takes time, you know?
Days, weeks.
It's knowing when to take that
shot, give yourself the best
chance to take down
that 10-point.
I mean, if you wanna get into
the Boone and Crockett Club,
it's gonna take time and um,
setting yourself up
for that perfect moment.
[Dalton on radio]
One shot, one kill.
[Pete on radio] Oh, yes.
Yes, I'm a student of
the muzzleloader.
One shot.
[intense music playing]
-[rain pattering]
-[thunder cracking]
[car door opens]
[car door closes]
[breathing heavily]
[car door opens]
[car door closes]
[engine starts]
[exhales]
[panting]
[munching]
You okay?
Yeah.
Are you nervous?
No.
Don't be nervous.
I'm not.
[nurse] There we are.
And there's an arm.
[chuckles]
[nurse] A foot.
[Rebecca laughs]
[nurse]
Do you wanna know the sex?
[Rebecca]
No, we wanna wait.
[nurse]
Do you wanna hear the heartbeat?
[nurse chuckles]
[heart thumping]
[Rebecca laughs]
[tense music playing]
[Rebecca] Simon.
Simon.
It's amazing.
It's--
I'm so happy.
[laughs]
[TV playing]
[Simon]
Thanks for being a voice.
Thanks for being an unafraid
voice that speaks the truth,
especially in times like these.
Everything is.
.everything
is so broken.
[Dalton on radio] Today, we're
talking about transportation
and the potential collapse of
this country's backbone.
What's happening to the
trucking industry?
Said it before and I'll say
it again, we don't value labor
anymore in this country.
We don't.
Now, I'm not saying
I'm anti-union.
Quite the contrary.
But we need a change of focus.
We need to turn the needle
back, get away from all this--
this automation.
These robots are gonna drive us
to an early extinction,
I'm telling you.
[machinery whirring]
[Will] Simon.
[knocking on door]
[door opens and closes]
Simon, this is Officer
Bondurant, Officer Sherman.
They got a few questions
for you.
Mr. Ward, we had a report filed
that you accosted a Peter Ellis
over at the WFBX studios.
-[laughs]
-That true?
No.
You didn't get into
a physical altercation?
No.
It was a misunderstanding and--
[Officer Sherman] Mr. Ellis
isn't pressing charges,
but the station filed
a restraining order against you.
You just can't go near
the properties anymore.
It's best to probably avoid it
altogether.
[laughs]
What's the charge?
We're not charging you.
It's a restraining order.
Look, just stay away
from the property
and you won't be in violation.
You got any questions for us?
All right.
Well, we appreciate it, fellas.
We'll let you get back to it.
You guys have a great day.
Thank you, guys.
[door opens]
[door closes]
Simon, what's this all about?
Nothing.
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter?
Guy was a fucking jerk,
all right?
And now I'm gonna pay the price
for it.
Simon, listen, buddy, you need
some time to refocus here.
I'm serious.
When the cops have to come
to your work and serve you
with a restraining order?
[chuckles]
Simon, I don't wanna fire you,
buddy,
but I am taking you off
the schedule for the time being.
I can't take time.
-[Will] Until you refocus--
-I have a baby coming.
-Okay? I can't take time.
-Well, this ain't voluntary.
This isn't right.
I didn't do anything.
Can you not see I'm tossing you
a lifeline here?
Buddy, I get it.
I do, I understand.
But I also think
this is what's best.
Mm-hmm.
I'll get Sal to cover for you.
No.
Fuck you. I quit.
-Simon.
-What?
Huh?
What?
Simon.
[door slams shut]
I'ma need your keys back, man.
Hey, Ward, look, come on, man,
wait a second.
Simon, look, look.
Listen.
[sighs]
I'm sorry about Parker,
all right?
[tense music playing]
[laughs]
You disgust me.
You fucking disgust me.
What?
I what?
[scoffs] I disgust you.
You ever follow me again
and I will fucking kill you.
Do you understand?
I will fucking kill you.
[♪♪♪]
[heavy breathing]
[grunts]
[cries, panting]
[car drives off]
[♪♪♪]
[gun loading]
[gunshot]
[bolt cycles]
[target carrier whirring]
[Dalton on radio]
More and more apparent
that our current political
system is failing us.
Had a chance to dig into some
13F filing released yesterday.
A 13F is a financial institution
report, mainly banks.
We're talking JP Morgan Chase,
Bank of America, PNC, et cetera.
They report that middle class
savings has dropped
$3.1 trillion in Q2.
[Rebecca on voicemail]
Hi, you've reached Rebecca.
I'm not in right now--
[Dalton on radio]
Did you hear me, people?
Middle class Americans
are seeing their
savings wiped out.
Are you upset?
You bet I'm f--
[bleeped] upset.
[car door opens]
[engine starts]
[♪♪♪]
[birds chirping]
[soft piano music playing]
[door opens and closes]
Simon?
[laughs]
Wow.
Is this for me?
-Sit.
-[laughs]
[chair scraping]
Thank you.
What is the special occasion?
I wanted to do something
special for you.
[drink pouring]
Wow.
Well, that is very sweet.
Thank you.
[Rebecca clears throat]
[chair scrapes]
This looks amazing.
[sighs]
How was your day?
Ugh, another day.
[laughs] We have this client
who's nearly in arrears,
but I think we should be able
to get his books straight
and get his cash flow
worked out, so.
-Right.
-[Rebecca] But we'll see.
I mean, half these people,
they don't understand money
at all, you know?
[laughs] And of course, I have
to be the one to argue with them
and explain how they even
ended up in this situation,
but it's like a foreign
language to them half the time.
I mean, you manage to start
a business, and yet you don't
understand how cash flow works?
I mean--
[Rebecca takes deep breath]
Oh, gosh.
And you know, of course,
I'm not a financial planner,
so I'm just dealing
with the bad news,
which they don't wanna hear,
but somebody has to explain
the books.
It's just blah, blah, blah,
and it's so annoying.
[Rebecca laughs]
I bet.
Sorry.
How was your day?
[chewing]
It was fine.
[Rebecca clears throat]
How was work?
Are you happy, Becca?
[laughs]
Yeah.
I'm-- yes.
Why?
Are you happy with us?
Of course, Simon.
Just asking.
Popped by your work today.
Oh, yeah?
When?
[Simon] Lunchtime.
Yeah.
I got off early, so I figured,
you know, mosey on by,
see if we can grab a bite
together.
But I missed you.
Your receptionist said that you
were um, you'd already left.
-Mm.
-You and uh,
a couple of co-workers.
[clears throat] Yeah, it was
a-- a working lunch thing.
How was it?
[Rebecca] Um, it was fine.
-[Simon] Hmm.
-[chuckles]
[clears throat]
[sips, gulps]
Uh, sorry, but um,
my stomach's not feeling so hot.
Are you okay?
Uh, yeah, yeah.
It's just um, pregnancy stuff.
I think I'm gonna go take
a shower and lay down.
Can I help you?
No, I'm-- I'm fine.
Thank you. This was um,
this was very nice.
[Rebecca sighs]
[heavy breathing]
[♪♪♪]
♪ Party shadows, they pursue ♪
[muffled screams]
♪ Here they come now to ♪
[indistinct lyrics]
♪ Talking at me, never to ♪
♪ Like a board game,
just guess who ♪
♪ Do you fucking know 'bout
crypto? ♪
♪ Sneakerhead, Sportsbet, MMA,
pure ket ♪
♪ Closest talker,
furthest truth ♪
♪ World's best dad drinks
from a shoe ♪
♪ No way, ya yappin',
ya chirpin', ya sleezin' ♪
♪ Ya gurnin' ♪
♪ No way, you still fucking
talking, mate ♪
♪ No way, ya yappin',
ya chirpin', ya sleezin' ♪
♪ Ya gurnin' ♪
♪ No way ♪
[gun clicks]
♪ You still fucking
talking, mate ♪
♪ You still fucking talking,
talking ♪
♪ You still fucking talk-- ♪
[intense music playing]
[handbrake ratchets]
-Hey.
-Yeah.
Whoa. Si-- Simon, wait, man.
-No, no, no, no, no, no.
-[Simon] Shut up.
-Okay.
-I'm not-- I'm not--
-[Simon] Look at me.
Look at me in the eyes, Dave!
-[Dave] Simon.
-Look at me!
I-- I-- I am. I am.
You're what's wrong with this
place, with this world.
-Not me.
-Hey, hey, hey, hey.
-You're the fucking problem.
-Whoa, Simon, Simon,
what are you doing?
Put that damn gun down.
Simon, put the gun down.
-I can't.
-[Will] Yes, you can.
Whatever I did, I'm so-- [cries]
I'm so sorry. Okay?
[Will] Put that gun down
and we'll talk about this.
No one listens anymore.
No one pays attention,
sees what I see.
You're the fucking problem.
-[Will] Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
-You're a bad fucking person.
-[Will] Simon.
-[Dave] Simon, I'm--
-I'm listening to you.
-[Will] Think about what you're
-.doing, Simon.
-[Simon] Shut the fuck up, Dave.
-Shut up!
-[Will] Simon, I listen.
I see it.
You know I see it.
But these people are
good people, Simon.
They're not your problem.
Dave's not your problem.
Okay? You need help, Simon.
That's what you need.
You need help.
We're here to help you.
You don't wanna hurt
these innocent people.
They're not innocent, Will.
He's not innocent.
He needs to be held responsible.
[Will] No, no.
People need to be accountable
for how they are.
It's up here, buddy.
It's all in your freaking head.
You need help, Simon.
Let us help you.
I can help you.
I wanna help you.
[Dave] My family's at home.
My son's gonna be 11.
He's-- he's gonna be 11.
I just wanna-- I wanna see him
later.
I'm sorry for everything.
-Please.
-[Will] Simon.
[Dave] My son needs me.
I just swear, I promised him
I'd--
[Will] Simon, stop
[Dave]
I promised him I'd come home.
-[Will] Let me help you.
-[Dave] I promised him.
-I wanna help you.
-And I'm sorry, Simon. Please.
Back the fuck off me!
Stop getting so fucking close
to me!
-Hey, buddy.
-[Dave] I'm sorry.
You realize what you're doing?
Come on, Simon.
[Dave] I'm sorry.
Don't follow me.
[footsteps receding]
Simon!
[engine starts]
[Dave cries]
Dave.
You okay?
You all right?
Somebody call the police.
I don't know. He said--
[cries]
-[Will] Come here, man.
-[Dave] What did I do?
What did I do?
[Will] Come here. Hop up.
Come on. Come on.
We gotta go in.
You okay?
I-- [pants]
Somebody call the police.
All right.
[panting]
[grunts]
[♪♪♪]
[banging]
[Dalton on radio] Simple.
Once you've made that decision,
you just pull that trigger.
Becoming a member of The Nation
has never been easier.
You'll have access to podcasts,
special interviews,
facts, books, event dates,
and more.
I'm your host, Dalton Kirby, and
I'm here to give you the untold,
unbiased, and uncensored truth.
[hyperventilating]
[Dalton on radio]
This is the only place
telling you how it is,
telling you what it is,
and what you can
do about it.
[exhales]
Said it before,
and I'll say it again.
[car door opens]
This world is getting
crazier and crazier, folks.
[car door closes]
It seems like there
is nothing left for us to do.
There ain't no saving it.
[door opens]
So I guess all that's
left for men like us to do is--
Good morning, how can--
oh my God!
[Dalton] Watch it burn
or strike the match.
We need more insurrection,
not less.
The way we're heading,
we're in for a second movement,
a wave, but that wave starts
with us.
A slow current.
Starts with you folks,
your spouse, your coworker,
your neighbor.
Gradually, slowly,
more and more, building.
We need you.
You are the change
this world needs.
Sorry, folks, if you can bear
with me for just one second.
My name is Simon Ward.
Long-time listener.
Listen, son.
Simon.
Listen, Simon.
No more lies.
You want the truth.
I'm gonna tell you the truth.
-Son, what-- what lies have we--
-Simon.
Simon.
Simon, what--
[♪♪♪]
Ladies and gentlemen,
you wouldn't believe
what just happened
in our studio.
A gentleman, Simon, patriot.
I'm not a patriot.
I'm not part of your nation.
I'm not.
[Dalton]
You're a patriot, son.
You had the-- you had the
fortitude to walk in here.
You had the-- the courage
to walk in here and--
and show me, show all of us
who you are.
That's the kind of man
I would be proud to know.
You're the kind of man who
embodies the meaning
of the word, metal.
Now, we're all just
truth-seekers here, Simon.
I-- I-- I--
I have a funny feeling
that's what you are as well.
I-- I-- I feel as though you're
seeking the truth,
and maybe we should do this.
You know, maybe we should just
discuss this.
Maybe you and I should sit down
like-- like two men.
Sit down and-- and-- and--
and-- and then--
No.
No more.
There is no truth.
It's just--
[gunshots]
[grunts]
[panting]
[grunts, pants]
[Dalton] We're all just
truth-seekers here, Simon.
And I believe that that's
what you're after, the truth.
So let's just sit down,
you and me, two men,
and discuss the truth.
[Simon] No.
No more.
There is no truth.
-It's just--
-[gunshot]
[groans]
[chokes, gasping]
[Dalton] Jesus Christ, Carl!
[choking]
[tense music playing]
Call the police.
Yes, sir.
-What the fuck?
-Yeah.
It's Carl Haywood.
Yeah, WFBX radio.
-Yeah.
-[sighs]
[Carl] Shots fired
in the radio station.
[sighs]
[Carl]
[indistinct] Please.
Thank you.
[takes deep breaths]
Ladies and gentlemen, you--
you are not going to believe
what just took place in the
studio not 10 seconds ago,
and I apologize if--
[inhales]
If I sound heated, but--
[sighs]
See, this is the shit
I'm talking about.
An armed assailant, a vigilante,
barged into the studio
with the intention
of murdering me.
Now, you heard me say
that exactly right, folks.
This sicko fucking lunatic
walked in here
and tried to take me out.
And this is the shit
we're talking about.
This is why we have to get
ready, folks!
This is why we have the right
to bear arms!
And if it-- if it weren't
for the quick thinking of
our security guard, Carl.
our security guard, Carl,
I-- I wouldn't be sitting here
right now, and I just,
I swear to God,
that's the bona fide fact.
I mean, can you imagine?
Can you imagine if Carl
wasn't armed?
Only you can protect yourself
from the crazy shit
out there, folks, from all
the-- the fucking crazies.
I-- I-- I'll tell you what,
because I just felt it
firsthand.
Boy, oh boy, oh boy, did I.
[takes deep breath]
Listen, I'm gonna, I'm gonna
cut this one short, okay?
Because, uh, I mean,
cops are on the way,
and uh, I'm not gonna lie,
I'ma go get myself a drink.
So, um, just don't forget,
we can do this together, people.
It starts with,
it starts with you.
It starts with us, so.
.come with me.
-[police siren wailing]
-[Dalton sighing]
[somber music playing]
[♪♪♪]
♪ I want you more than
I need you ♪
♪ I need you so bad ♪
♪ Are you coming back? ♪
♪ I'm waiting ♪
♪ Haven't had a dream
in a long time ♪
♪ Haven't been able to sleep ♪
♪ Are you coming back? ♪
♪ I'm waiting ♪
♪ I want you more than
I need you ♪
♪ I need you bad ♪
♪ Are you coming back? ♪
♪ I'm waiting ♪
[♪♪♪]
[music fades]
[upbeat music playing]
[♪♪♪]
♪ Just for tonight, we'll
pretend that nobody's watching ♪
♪ On the dance floor ♪
♪ We can go to a place
where the stars are brighter ♪
♪ Than you've ever seen before ♪
♪ Just for tonight,
we'll pretend that ♪
♪ Our problems
from yesterday don't exist ♪
♪ If you want, we can go back to
the place where we first met ♪
♪ Just for tonight,
we'll pretend the sun ♪
♪ Ain't coming up
in the morning ♪
♪ Just for tonight,
we'll remember that ♪
♪ We only have tonight ♪
♪ Just for tonight,
let's light the fire ♪
♪ I'll be alright
with you by my side ♪
♪ Just for tonight, it feels so
right looking in your eyes ♪
♪ I forget about everything ♪
♪ Just for tonight, we'll
pretend that we are famous ♪
♪ Like the movie stars ♪
♪ We can dress up and wear
our favorite outfits ♪
♪ To our favorite bars ♪
♪ Just for tonight,
we'll pretend that ♪
♪ It's just you and me
and nobody else ♪
♪ We can cruise down the
interstate ♪
♪ With the windows down
and the music up ♪
♪ Just for tonight,
we'll pretend the sun ♪
♪ Ain't coming up
in the morning ♪
♪ Just for tonight,
we'll remember that
♪ We only have tonight ♪
♪ Just for tonight,
let's light the fire ♪
♪ I'll be alright
with you by my side ♪
♪ Just for tonight, it feels
so right looking in your eyes ♪
♪ I forget about everything ♪
[music fades]